census.gov.uk 2011-08-02

# Privacy Statement - 2011 Census

Your privacy is very important to us. We aim to be as clear as possible about how and why we use information about you on this website. This statement explains how we will use and protect any information that you give us when you visit this website. 

## Scope

This privacy statement relates to the internet services provided as part of the 2011 Census. These services include the online census, the online help centre and online requests for additional questionnaires and other services. They also include the online press centre and publicity websites.

## What information do we collect and why?

We collect three kinds of information from you: the answers you give when you complete our online questionnaire, your name and address (if you ask for any materials to be sent to you) and site usage information. 

Your online census answers are combined with those we collect from returned paper questionnaires. This information is used to produce statistics which help government and local authorities to plan and allocate funding to public services and support further research over the next ten years. 

Your name and address will only be used if you request additional materials from us, so that we can post them to you. You can either enter your name and address details yourself, or provide the questionnaire ID printed on the paper questionnaire so that we can retrieve your address information automatically. Your name and address details are not passed to any other government. No personal information is stored on the computer you are using. 

The information we gather from site usage is analysed to understand how the site is being used. We need to do this to make sure it is working effectively and providing the correct information to support the census. 

## Who will see your census information?

Your census information is used only by the Office for National Statistics (ONS). It is not shared with any other government departments. Access to your information is strictly controlled to ensure confidentiality.

## How long do we keep your information?

ONS holds your information securely for 100 years, after which it will be made available to family historians and other interested parties

## What are cookies and why do we use them?

 **PLEASE NOTE: The 2011 Census questionnaire website is no longer live. The following applies to the Census Stakeholder and Publicity website only.**

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. Cookies cannot be used to identify you personally. 

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example: recognising style and accessibility preferences you may have selected so you don't need to do it for every web page requested. 

You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them at: [](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "This link will open in a new window")http://www.aboutcookies.org/

### Our use of cookies

One of the cookies we use is essential for parts of the site to operate and has already been set. You may delete and block all cookies from this site. If you choose not to accept the cookies, this will not affect your access to the majority of facilities available on our website, but parts of the site will not work. 

The following table provides details about the cookies we use and why we use them: 

Cookie| Name| Purpose| Expiry| 1st or 3rd party?| Further information  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
Essential website cookie| PHPSESSID| This cookie is essential for the online notification form to operate and is set upon your arrival to the 2011 census website. This cookie is deleted when you leave our website| At the end of the session| 1st| Open source  
Language cookie| Lang| Determines whether you have selected to view our website in English or Welsh so that a consistent language is presented throughout your visit. This cookie is deleted when you leave our website| At the end of the session| 1st| Written specifically for this application  
Style cookie| Style| Remembers throughout your visit the background colour and text contrast selection you have chosen to view our website with (selectable from the top right-hand corner on each page)| 1 year| 1st| Written specifically for this application  
Font cookie| Font_size| Remembers throughout your visit the font size you have chosen to view our website with (selectable from the top right-hand corner on each page)| 1 year| 1st| Written specifically for this application  
  
Census also has links at the base of the left hand menu on each page so you can use social networking websites with 2011 Census. These websites may place cookies on your computer. You should refer to each website’s statement on cookies for further information.

## Security

Under the Data Protection Act, the Census Act 1920, the Statistics & Registration Services Act (SRSA) 2007 and Census Act (NI) 1969, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading security technologies, including industry-standard SSL encryption software, when processing sensitive information to safeguard your data and we apply strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it.   

## Phishing

Phishing (pronounced ’fishing‘) refers to deceptive emails and other communications usually designed to trick you into revealing your personal information. Phishing emails often appear to come from legitimate sources. Census will never send you an unsolicited email in relation to the 2011 Census.    

## Protecting yourself

While we will make sure your information is collected and held securely, there are some additional steps that you can take to protect yourself and your personal information while using this site. 

  * Keep your Internet Access Code and Questionnaire ID safe. It is specific to your household and should be treated as confidential information. 
  * Keep your web browsers and firewalls software up to date. 
  * Use only the official census website to gain access to the online questionnaire, using the website address printed on the front page of your paper questionnaire. 
  * Be sure to log out and close your browser after using the site. Closing a tab in your browser may not be enough. Note that after a period of ten minutes of inactivity, the site will automatically end your session. 
  * Once you have submitted your questionnaire we recommend that you print your confirmation receipt. 
  * You will be able to safely dispose of your paper questionnaire once you've submitted it. You should destroy/and or remove your name, address and internet access code on the front page, and then dispose of the rest of the questionnaire as you would any other personal document.

## Submitting your responses

If you start the 2011 Census online questionnaire but forget to click the ‘Submit’ button at the end, we will capture any information that you have entered and add it to the response database. We will do this when the online questionnaire system is no longer live. 

## Correcting your responses

If you think you have made a mistake, your responses can be corrected by navigating to the question and amending the answer. It is not possible to correct your responses once you have completed and submitted your questionnaire. 

## Changes to this policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page will make sure you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it. 

_27 May 2011_
